<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac OS on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/mac-os/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac OS on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/mac-os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Irssi and SASL on OSX</title>
      <link>/posts/irssi-and-sasl-on-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/irssi-and-sasl-on-osx/</guid>
      <description>Given my renewed focus on security I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking to lock down much of my communications so that I feel more secure online. One of the things that I use quite a lot to connect with people who know WTF they&amp;rsquo;re talking about is IRC. #freenode is my network of choice as it has a bunch of interesting places with fairly active communities. irssi is my current client of choice for a few reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What About Going the Other Way?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-about-going-the-other-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-about-going-the-other-way/</guid>
      <description>I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d add this last post as a bit of food for thought before signing off today. This link comes from a bloke who&amp;rsquo;s been through the pain of wanting to move away from Windows, only to find that the results were just as, if not more, painful than sticking to what he knew. Have a read of this blog entry to see that the grass isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily greener.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Vista Stuff-Up</title>
      <link>/posts/virtual-vista-stuff-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/virtual-vista-stuff-up/</guid>
      <description>OK, so it looks like I might have been misinformed (er&amp;hellip; wrong :)) by stating that the basic versions of Vista can&amp;rsquo;t be installed on VMs. That&amp;rsquo;ll teach me not to read the licencing details properly myself! It looks like it was a slight misunderstanding of the terms and structure that MS used in stating the rules. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details myself since Ed Bott has already done it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>