<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funny on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/funny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funny on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/funny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactivate? AGAIN!?</title>
      <link>/posts/reactivate-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reactivate-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post to say how much Microsoft and their draconian OS licensing mechanism are pissing me off right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my computer stopped booting. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to looking at it until a few days ago because I had visitors over from the UK. Not just that, it is Christmas, and the last thing you want to be doing on your Christmas break is to be fixing computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Order Tracking</title>
      <link>/posts/online-order-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/online-order-tracking/</guid>
      <description>This is me while I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for my Buffalo Terastation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swear Jar</title>
      <link>/posts/the-swear-jar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-swear-jar/</guid>
      <description>I know this is doing the rounds at the moment, but I had to post in case you&amp;rsquo;ve not seen it. It&amp;rsquo;s classic!  Click here to go to the YouTube site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beatbox Fame Game</title>
      <link>/posts/beatbox-fame-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/beatbox-fame-game/</guid>
      <description>I generally don&amp;rsquo;t like to post links that I&amp;rsquo;ve been sent without discussing them a bit, but in this case I just can&amp;rsquo;t resist. It warrants no discussion - it just has to be watched. Check this out, it&amp;rsquo;s awesome! 
Beatbox Fame GameGenius!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI Punishment</title>
      <link>/posts/ci-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ci-punishment/</guid>
      <description>For a development to succeed in its use of a continuous integration process there must be a sufficiently hefty deterrent to prevent people from breaking the build. If you break the build, you should feel some form of retribution to aid in stopping you from doing it again.
Plip&amp;rsquo;s recently posted a suggestion for this very issue. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic idea! Make sure you print it and stick it up in your office!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Were the Wiggles Software Developers?</title>
      <link>/posts/were-the-wiggles-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/were-the-wiggles-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Some of you might not know about The Wiggles, but those of you who are either Australian or have any connection with an extremely young family member will probably have a fair idea. In short, they&amp;rsquo;re a collection of dudes who do performances for kiddies, and have managed to make themselves a fortune putting smiles on the dials of kids all over the world. Hats off to them!
The question I&amp;rsquo;m asking isn&amp;rsquo;t serious ;) But I have to ask it because I think that one of their famous songs has been written with my current software development project in mind!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Away from that Computer!</title>
      <link>/posts/get-away-from-that-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/get-away-from-that-computer/</guid>
      <description>I know I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t laugh about this, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help it :)
Any geek that&amp;rsquo;s in a relationship has probably heard the words &amp;ldquo;GET AWAY FROM THAT !$@*ING COMPUTER!&amp;rdquo; (or something along those lines) more than once. Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, you might have heard it from your mum when you were a budding geek (as I was).
After reading this article on The Inquirer I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think that this bloke had hard that phrase possibly one too many times?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get FartFox</title>
      <link>/posts/get-fartfox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/get-fartfox/</guid>
      <description>I came across some info on The Inquirer earlier today regarding Firefox&amp;rsquo;s logo (shown on the right) that&amp;rsquo;s being used for the Japanese version. As the link above states:The new logo for its Japanese Fire Fox, Foxkeh, was apparently chosen out of a field of 600.How could they not see the issue with the image before releasing it to the world?
Not that it matters ;) I like the logo - it implies that Firefox is shit hot, which I think it is :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It has begun</title>
      <link>/posts/it-has-begun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/it-has-begun/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who know me will know that I generally feel like I have a lot to say :-) I used to write a diary back in the day, but that was quite some time ago and the site, along with its content, is long since dead. For the last couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve been continually reading people&amp;rsquo;s blogs and found they can be quite insightful. As a geek, I tend to read more geek blogs which cover upcoming technologies, opinions on methodologies and other bits of flotsam and jetsam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>