<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Go With Your Instinct</title>
      <link>/posts/go-with-your-instinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/go-with-your-instinct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2011/02/double-facepalm.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2011/02/double-facepalm.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; style=&#34;float:left;margin-right:5px;margin-bottom:5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;At an early age I realised that it&amp;rsquo;s not always a bad thing to go with your first instinct. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the reasons here, nor the way I came to that conclusion. What I will say is that I wish I&amp;rsquo;d listened to my inner-8-year-old-self when I started down the thread of emails and Tweets you&amp;rsquo;re about to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice is to say that I have learned my lesson!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thread speaks for itself. Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N Things You Don&#39;t Want to Hear when Starting a New Job (where N &amp;gt;= 1)</title>
      <link>/posts/n-things-you-dont-want-to-hear-when-starting-a-new-job-where-n-gt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/n-things-you-dont-want-to-hear-when-starting-a-new-job-where-n-gt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are a collection of quotes that can drive fear into the heart of every developer. They&amp;rsquo;re made worse when heard at the start of a new gig, as any hope of a brave new world is smashed before you even get a login!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Resolutions</title>
      <link>/posts/random-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/random-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to make New Years Resolutions. I think they&amp;rsquo;re a bit of a wank to be honest. But I do love a good gimmick. So when I stumbled on this I both loved and hated it.
 This first attempt made me chuckle. I think all the time, let alone at inappropriate times. The bigger question is: what should I be thinking about at inappropriate times?.
Who knows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve Caved-in to Twitter</title>
      <link>/posts/ive-caved-in-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ive-caved-in-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I was against the idea for ages, but for some reason I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start using it. Twitter was one of those things that I didn&amp;rsquo;t see a need for. Now I can.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be using it to keep track of ideas I have for blog posts as well as other things that I need to get done. If you feel like tracking me or joining me in a conversation, please feel free to add me to your follow list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Keyword Searches</title>
      <link>/posts/interesting-keyword-searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/interesting-keyword-searches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was browsing through my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics&#34; title=&#34;Google Analytics&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; stats earlier and thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to browse through search terms that resulted in a hit on my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man, there are some crazy entries!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Sound in the World</title>
      <link>/posts/the-best-sound-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-best-sound-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is hearing your Son laugh out loud for the first time.
Solid gold. &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are the Champions!</title>
      <link>/posts/we-are-the-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/we-are-the-champions/</guid>
      <description>It has been a long time coming (somewhere around the 70 year mark - I think the last time was 1939) but we finally got there. Pompey made it to the FA Cup final. Not only did we get there, but we managed to beat the opposition, Cardiff, 1 - 0.
Yes, this is one of the few times I&amp;rsquo;ll ever admit to being born anywhere near Portsmouth ;) It&amp;rsquo;s good to see the lads come up with a win after a pretty good run in the Premier League in the last couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>62 Days To Go</title>
      <link>/posts/62-days-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/62-days-to-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just come back from another run and again I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good. I did the same route as yesterday, but 6 minutes slower. It was encouraging that I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel out of breath or overly tired, the thing that got me was sore legs!
Tomorrow is going to be a rest day because I have to go and do a certification exam during lunch time which is a bit annoying. Hopefully Wednesday lunch time I&amp;rsquo;ll be rested up and ready to take on the lunchtime route again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Training Update</title>
      <link>/posts/marathon-training-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/marathon-training-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since before &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/more-punishment/&#34; title=&#34;More Punishment&#34;&gt;signing up for the marathon&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been making sure that I do my running training regularly. I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing at least 4 runs during the week, pushing for 5 (all during lunch times). The route that I run around the city is approximately 6.2km, which is a good distance to cover while still having time either side of the run for prepration and showering up so that I don&amp;rsquo;t offend my coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Punishment</title>
      <link>/posts/more-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/more-punishment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 3 years on the bench I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take the plunge again. Today I signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goldcoastmarathon.com.au/&#34; title=&#34;Gold Coast Airport Marahon&#34;&gt;Gold Coast Airport Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The event will be held on the 6th July &amp;lsquo;08 &amp;ndash; which from today means I have a total of 80 more days to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been back into running training for a few weeks now, and have been really enjoying it. Lunch time runs are really helping since I don&amp;rsquo;t have a great deal of time in the evenings to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Hours</title>
      <link>/posts/8-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/8-hours/</guid>
      <description>A timespan like this probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that much to you.
It does to me.
Thank you, Marley, for such a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Because the Cost of Living is Getting so High, High, High</title>
      <link>/posts/because-the-cost-of-living-is-getting-so-high-high-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/because-the-cost-of-living-is-getting-so-high-high-high/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xavierrudd.com/&#34; title=&#34;Xavier Rudd&#34;&gt;Xavier Rudd&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelyricarchive.com/song/1721539-223666/Famine&#34; title=&#34;Famine&#34;&gt;hit the nail on the head&lt;/a&gt; with that song. It&amp;rsquo;s becoming more and more evident that our cash isn&amp;rsquo;t going as far as it used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been very difficult not to notice that the cost of everything we do is just sky-rocketing. Today, after another extremely expensive trip to the shops, it hit me full in the face.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He&#39;s a Man-Machine!</title>
      <link>/posts/hes-a-man-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hes-a-man-machine/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to publicly announce some serious kudos to a good mate of mine, Matt Tamsett. Matt&amp;rsquo;s a bloke I met while working in the games industry in the UK a couple of years back, who now lives in Brisbane too. He&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a fitness freak, and last year decided to sign up for the Ironman event in New Zealand. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this would have to be the most gruelling Triathlon on the planet (or close to it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do your bit for the Earth</title>
      <link>/posts/do-your-bit-for-the-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/do-your-bit-for-the-earth/</guid>
      <description>First post in a while, I guess I must have been busy with something ;) More on that later.
I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d do my little bit for the world and spread the word about Earth Hour. Sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like anything drastic in the grand scheme of things, but every little bit helps. So check it out, sign up and do your bit with me!
Hope you&amp;rsquo;re all doing well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Boy</title>
      <link>/posts/my-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-boy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2008/02/cimg3655.JPG&#34; title=&#34;Marley Reeves&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2008/02/cimg3655.JPG&#34; width=&#34;125&#34; alt=&#34;Marley Reeves&#34; style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 3px; padding-bottom: 3px; border: 0;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure that most of you don&amp;rsquo;t give a hoot about how often I post. But those of you who do, and who have noticed that I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted for a little while may want to know why. The answer is: &lt;strong&gt;I have become a Father!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Downtime</title>
      <link>/posts/server-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/server-downtime/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are millions of adoring fans out there (ha!) that were wondering where the site has been the last few days. Our host, VPSLink had a huge issue with a RAID array being corrupted, and it just so happened that our site was on that node. Such is life!?
The result was a little under two days downtime, and at least a day of extremely poor performance from the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era</title>
      <link>/posts/the-end-of-an-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-end-of-an-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2007/12/newgemmell.jpg&#34; title=&#34;David Gemmell - 1948 to 2006&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2007/12/newgemmell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Gemmell - 1948 to 2006&#34; class=&#34;InlineImageRight&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Whenever people ask me who my favourite author is, I always reply with the same answer. He&amp;rsquo;s a fairly well-known guy, particularly in the heroic fantasty and sci-fi circles. His name is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Gemmell&#34; title=&#34;David Gemmell&#34;&gt;David Gemmell&lt;/a&gt;, and this post is a mini dedication to him and his career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first discovered the joys of David&amp;rsquo;s writing when a dear friend of mine, Simon C, allowed me to borrow one of his books. It was called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Legend-David-Gemmell/dp/0345913779/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1196748787&amp;sr=1-1&#34; title=&#34;Legend&#34;&gt;Legend&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a fascinating and enthralling story. If I remember correctly, it took me but a couple of days of after school reading to get throug it. It was easy reading. The kind of book that you just don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to put down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Day for Me, a Sad Day for my Country</title>
      <link>/posts/a-great-day-for-me-a-sad-day-for-my-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-great-day-for-me-a-sad-day-for-my-country/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the good news. Today is my first ever wedding anniversary! This last year seems to have flown by. In many ways it feels like I got married a few weeks ago, and yet in other ways it feels like so much has happened.
It really has been an amazing year. I&amp;rsquo;m an extremely lucky man and honestly couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier. I won&amp;rsquo;t get too sooky, but I just wanted to say that my wife makes my life complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Artistic Outlet</title>
      <link>/posts/my-artistic-outlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-artistic-outlet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people who trundle through life, battling against the elements and working hard to achieve at work or in the home find that they need an escape. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about just a holiday to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitsundaytourism.com/&#34; title=&#34;Whitsundays&#34;&gt;Whitsundays&lt;/a&gt; or a month off to go hiking in the Himalayas. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about something more regular. Something that perhaps you can do on a daily basis to help you feel more relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few. I like to do distance running. At the moment my training regime is almost non-existant because of the stuff that&amp;rsquo;s going on, but that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m going to remedy shortly. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go for runs during lunchtimes again now that I&amp;rsquo;m somewhere which has a clean shower! I find that a good long run can really make me feel good. Nothing like a bit of cardio excercise followed by a hit of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endorphin&#34; title=&#34;Endorphin&#34;&gt;endorphins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Mixed Bag</title>
      <link>/posts/a-little-mixed-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-little-mixed-bag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the last time I posted a couple of things have happened that are worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, my dear mate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shiftperception.com/&#34; title=&#34;Shiftperception&#34;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; and his lovely girl, Ailin, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shiftperception.com/blog/posts/were-married/&#34; title=&#34;We&#39;re Married!&#34;&gt;got married on the 6th October&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic day and I was honoured to be part of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I started a new job. A little while ago I received an offer that was too good to miss, and I decided to make the jump. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an easy decision (it never is), but I do think it&amp;rsquo;s the right one. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to mention where I am, nor where I came from. But I can at least pass on a few details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Talk About Politics</title>
      <link>/posts/dont-talk-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dont-talk-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to break a cardinal rule. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about politics (but only briefly). If you&amp;rsquo;re not Australian, or don&amp;rsquo;t have an interest in Australian politics, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest you give this post a miss :)
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in front of the T.V. watching the Leaders Debate, and I have to say that I&amp;rsquo;m appalled at some of the utter dribble that is coming out of Kevin Rudd&amp;rsquo;s mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not OJ Simpson</title>
      <link>/posts/i-am-not-oj-simpson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/i-am-not-oj-simpson/</guid>
      <description>In recent weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve seen interesting patterns of traffic to the site. I have been trying to figure out exactly what leads people here, but it has been a hard thing to put a finger on (despite the amazing functionality of Google Analytics). I had a sneaking suspicion for a while that I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting hits from those people who are looking for information on OJ Simpson. Two days ago that was confirmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Me Help You!</title>
      <link>/posts/help-me-help-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/help-me-help-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only in the Movies... and at Home.</title>
      <link>/posts/only-in-the-movies...-and-at-home./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/only-in-the-movies...-and-at-home./</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s an age-old story: boy rings babysitter, boy harasses babysitter over the phone while slowly torturing babysitter&amp;rsquo;s boyfriend and telly babysitter that she&amp;rsquo;s next.
You see this thing in the movies all the time, to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s considered cliched. When the idea of it first came out, it was really quite freaky. Now that it&amp;rsquo;s been done to death, when I see it in a movie I automagically react by turning the movie off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search is Over</title>
      <link>/posts/the-search-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-search-is-over/</guid>
      <description>I now have an answer to the question that I implied in my previous post (ie. is the search over?)! The answer is: Yes! The search is over!
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into all the gory and graphic details (this is, after all, a publicly viewable blog), but I can say that after a single round of negotiation with the owner of the said block of land, we&amp;rsquo;ve settled on a price and we&amp;rsquo;re in the throws of getting it sorted out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search Might be Over</title>
      <link>/posts/the-search-might-be-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-search-might-be-over/</guid>
      <description>Today we may well have come to the end of our search. Tomorrow morning, at 8am, we meet the Real Estate agent and if things go to plan, we may well be making an offer on a block of land! How exciting. Check out the pic to see what we&amp;rsquo;re contemplating ;) It&amp;rsquo;s just over an acre, and looks to be exactly what we&amp;rsquo;ve been searching for.
I&amp;rsquo;ll post again tomorrow and let you know how it goes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Image</title>
      <link>/posts/banner-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/banner-image/</guid>
      <description>Yup, it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely, positively disgusting :) And yes, it highlights my artistic abilities. Well, actually, it highlights my lack of motivation to actually come up with something coo so I instead hacked out the existing text and threw in something else. I know it&amp;rsquo;s horrid :) I&amp;rsquo;m waiting patiently for me main man Dan to come up with something groovey that I can use instead - so this will have to do in the mean time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisbane Real Estate</title>
      <link>/posts/brisbane-real-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/brisbane-real-estate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;ve been home from the U.K., Amy and I have been keeping tabs on the property market in the hope of finding a place that we&amp;rsquo;d be keen to buy. We&amp;rsquo;ve been renting ever since we&amp;rsquo;ve known each other, and I started renting over 10 years ago. This probably won&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise, but I&amp;rsquo;m bloody sick of renting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m lining the pockets of my landlord, I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea that the money we&amp;rsquo;re putting into our living arrangements is just dead. We won&amp;rsquo;t ever see it again. So, it&amp;rsquo;s now well past the time that we found our own place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One would have thought that finding a house to buy would be a &lt;em&gt;relatively&lt;/em&gt; easy thing to do, but given the state of the property market here in Brisbane, it&amp;rsquo;s proven to be a very tough thing to do. The market here has been so buoyant for the last few years that prices have gone through the roof. There are currently 1200 (approx) people moving to South-East Queensland every &lt;strong&gt;week&lt;/strong&gt;, and hence there is a dire need for housing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noisy Neighbours</title>
      <link>/posts/noisy-neighbours/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/noisy-neighbours/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been renting for over 10 years now, and in my time I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced quite a few different types of neighbours. Some of them were really friendly - they&amp;rsquo;d invite themselves in for a cup of tea, hang about for a while to have a yarn before heading back to their own place. Some wouldn&amp;rsquo;t speak a word and would make an obvious effort to stay away from me (arguably a wise choice :) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Constitutes a &#39;Tutorial&#39;?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-constitutes-a-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-constitutes-a-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I read lots articles, tutorials and whitepapers whenever I get the chance. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll read something and feel enlightened. Other times I finish and feel that I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow lost brain cells (please, no jokes about having none to lose ;) ). Recently some of the tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the web have left me feeling extremely underwhelmed. The reasons are because I felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn anything or that the tutorial, while hitting the point, didn&amp;rsquo;t actually feel like it delivered the kind of information I was expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve Moved ... Again!</title>
      <link>/posts/weve-moved-...-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weve-moved-...-again/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year again - time to move servers! I hope that this is going to be the last one for quite some time as I&amp;rsquo;m getting sick of it :) The current set up looks to be a good one and I can&amp;rsquo;t (at the moment) see why we&amp;rsquo;d need to change it again.
Let me know if you see any issues with the new server!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you Enjoy what you do for a Living?</title>
      <link>/posts/do-you-enjoy-what-you-do-for-a-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/do-you-enjoy-what-you-do-for-a-living/</guid>
      <description>I remember when I was in high school as a teenager and all I wanted to &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo; was a Software Engineer. I was one of those lucky people who always seemed to know what it is they wanted to do, and for me it was always going to be creating software. I got stuck into a plethora of coding projects in my own time while finishing school which, along with doing &amp;ldquo;Computer Studies&amp;rdquo; for the last 3 years, gave me a pretty solid grounding to build on when I got to University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are you Really Looking at?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-are-you-really-looking-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-are-you-really-looking-at/</guid>
      <description>We all know that the pictures that we find in magazines, posters and movies are edited. A lot. But it&amp;rsquo;s hard to really get a good idea of what actually goes on behind the scenes until you see something like this. Scary eh? Makes you realise that absolutely anyone can be &amp;ldquo;model material&amp;rdquo; as long as they have a stack of make-up and a friend who&amp;rsquo;s good enough with photoshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Install Vista?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-i-install-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/should-i-install-vista/</guid>
      <description>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a question directed at you guys :) This is a question that lots of people have been asking me of late, and I felt the need to answer the question once and for all. The short answer is: No.The medium answer is: I have a licenced copy because I am an MSDN subscriber and I still haven&amp;rsquo;t installed it. So what does that tell you?The long answer is: If you are looking for an operating system that chews up a lot of resources, behaves like Windows XP with a new coat of paint, doesn&amp;rsquo;t play nicely with most of the games on the market, takes away your rights as a user and consumer of most forms of digital content and gives you constant issues with your hardware, then yes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport is Good For You</title>
      <link>/posts/sport-is-good-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sport-is-good-for-you/</guid>
      <description>I love my sport. Without it I&amp;rsquo;d go nuts. It&amp;rsquo;s a great venting mechanism, it lets you burn off calories and makes you feel good.
Unfortunately, not every sporting session turns out the way you&amp;rsquo;d like it. You might lose a game, or run a bad time, or twist your ankle - you might even get clobbered by someone on the opposite team and end up in quite a bit of pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bad Workman Blames his Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/a-bad-workman-blames-his-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-bad-workman-blames-his-tools/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used this saying a fair few times in my life, and today I was shown something that I think backs the statement up nicely. This is an example of an amazing Workman with a poor tool - and look at what he creates:
How to draw a car in MS. Paint
Simply amazing :) Thanks for the link Ryan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look</title>
      <link>/posts/a-new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-new-look/</guid>
      <description>I was getting sick of the way the site was looking, so I changed it. I know I&amp;rsquo;ll end up changing it again because I&amp;rsquo;ll no doubt get sick of looking at the site layout as well, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with it. It&amp;rsquo;s a hacked version of a theme that I thought was nice, but I felt it needed some modifications. I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% finished yet, as I think the top of the page just looks bare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality of Service</title>
      <link>/posts/quality-of-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quality-of-service/</guid>
      <description>First of all, Happy New Year!
Now that the formalities are out of the way, I&amp;rsquo;ll get stuck into the post :)
Today&amp;rsquo;s comments are inspired a by a recent experience I had with an online form (of all things!). Being a bit of a game geek, both in the &amp;lsquo;build&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;play&amp;rsquo; senses, I constantly read a lot of gaming stuff. One thing that I&amp;rsquo;m a fairly regular reader of is GamaSutra, as it&amp;rsquo;s got lots of juicy game development stuff in it - a great read for people such as myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life, the Universe and Everything.</title>
      <link>/posts/life-the-universe-and-everything./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/life-the-universe-and-everything./</guid>
      <description>42??
It&amp;rsquo;s been quite some time since I&amp;rsquo;ve had a proper rant, and now that the wedding is over and I have a bit more spare time I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take the chance to dump some more thoughts about something we all want to know about &amp;hellip; stuff!!
Today&amp;rsquo;s stuff regards issues around work-life balance and what makes me happy doing what I do for a living. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a broad topic, but one that I consider to be pretty damned important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love is in the Air</title>
      <link>/posts/love-is-in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/love-is-in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t take that title too lightly, I do actually mean it! If it&amp;rsquo;s not currently boarding a flight to Mexico, it&amp;rsquo;s already in the air somewhere over NSW!
For those of you who haven&amp;rsquo;t cottoned on yet (which is probably everyone) I&amp;rsquo;m talking about our dear friends Dan and Ailin (Dan being the Dan from shifty) have just got&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; ENGAGED!!!!!!!!
Boy did that kick the day off on a very excited foot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Album Uploaded</title>
      <link>/posts/web-album-uploaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/web-album-uploaded/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d best get in quickly before all the emails start coming in asking &amp;ldquo;where are the $*^ING PHOTOS!??!&amp;rdquo; and get a web album up so that you guys can all see evidence of the amazing time that I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the last couple of weeks.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used Picassa and the Google web album feature to get a stack of pictures up, and you can find them all here. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting again in a while and letting you all know about the good, the bad and the ugly with regards to getting our wedding organised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you see me Waving?</title>
      <link>/posts/can-you-see-me-waving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/can-you-see-me-waving/</guid>
      <description>Hi all! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I posted last, but for very good reason. I&amp;rsquo;ve been away since the 17th of Nov sorting out various things, packing up and moving south for a short holiday. The reason - I got married!
After over 6 years of being together Amy and I tied the knot on the 24th of Nov &amp;lsquo;06. The day was an absolute corker, and without sounding cliched, it was the best day of my life to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCs for the Family</title>
      <link>/posts/pcs-for-the-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pcs-for-the-family/</guid>
      <description>I know for sure that many of the geeks out there on the World Wide Wibbly have the &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; task of sorting out every possible computer issue for any/all of their family and friends in the cases where they&amp;rsquo;re not geeks themselves. I am one such geek, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest and say that I do not mind helping out. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a bit of fun! I starting pondering thoughts on this topic when I stumbled across Roy&amp;rsquo;s MomPC blog post a week or two ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration</title>
      <link>/posts/iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/iteration/</guid>
      <description>I found a pretty inspiring video the other day that I think is a perfect visual representation of what should happen in software. OK, that&amp;rsquo;s not quite true, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it, I was given it by none other than Dan the man (@shifty). The video is a time-lapsed video of someone drawing a picture of a wasp-like insect (I don&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be cluey in the world of insects, so just be happy with that description :)), but the beauty of it is that you can see how the final product evolves as the picture is iterated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Blogging</title>
      <link>/posts/the-joy-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-joy-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this link archived for a little while, and today&amp;rsquo;s the day I decided to be arsed to comment on it. A long-term blogger known as Greg posted about what he&amp;rsquo;s learned about blogging in his 2000th blog post. I enjoyed reading it, and it made me ask myself the questions: What do you get out of blogging?What is it you want to get out of bloggingDo you feel like you have to post at least once per day?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Computer</title>
      <link>/posts/pumpkin-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pumpkin-computer/</guid>
      <description>I had to post this for the masses/geeks to enjoy (though chances are that you&amp;rsquo;ve already seen it if you&amp;rsquo;re a Gizmodo reader). Some chap decided to make himself a computer made from a pumpkin (well, for the chassis). Yup, another geek with too much time (and pumpkin) on his hands. I wonder how long it&amp;rsquo;s going to take before it starts to stink!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groovey Honda Commercial</title>
      <link>/posts/groovey-honda-commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/groovey-honda-commercial/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick post for you guys this morning. Me ol&amp;rsquo; mucka Tommy Lee pointed me at a cool website this morning with a link to YouTube - The Best Honda Commercial Ever. Very cool stuff! Check it out. Apparently, all the sound effects were made by people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GooTube</title>
      <link>/posts/gootube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gootube/</guid>
      <description>Yes this is old news to anyone who reads any form of news :) But Google have bought YouTube! How exciting. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m very happy for those lads who set YouTube up in the first place. The idea was based on the need to share some large homes videos of parties with mates who weren&amp;rsquo;t there, and it&amp;rsquo;s turned into a multi-billion dollar empire. It&amp;rsquo;s good to hear that there are people out there like this still making something big for themselves for having the balls to give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott Adams&#39; Blog</title>
      <link>/posts/scott-adams-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/scott-adams-blog/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably all guessed by now that I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a Dilbert fan, especially considering that it feels like a I work with most of those characters!
While browsing through the recent cartoons, I noticed that there was a link to Scott Adam&amp;rsquo;s Blog which I proceeded to follow and I was greeted with some really interesting reading. So if you&amp;rsquo;ve got some time to kill and are interested in getting into the amazing mind of the man behind Dilbert, get on over there and have a read!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve moved!</title>
      <link>/posts/weve-moved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weve-moved/</guid>
      <description>Boy that was quick! I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s still some DNS servers out there that need to be updated, but things certainly moved quickly. Blackapache is now on a new server, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty darned happy with the ease and speed of the move. Not just that, but this new location feels a heck of a lot faster than the old one.
So we&amp;rsquo;re back online! Feel free to continue commenting/posting. I&amp;rsquo;ll be back later (possibly even later today) with some thoughts on episodic gaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server change imminent</title>
      <link>/posts/server-change-imminent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/server-change-imminent/</guid>
      <description>In the next couple of days Blackapache is going to be shifting to a new server. There are a few reasons for this, but the main one is the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated and unimpressed with the level of service I&amp;rsquo;m getting with the current provider. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to directly state who it is, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to find it out ;)
I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving my site, and a couple of others, to a server here in Australia where the speed and quality of service is substantially higher thanks to NetLogistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minority Report becomes Reality?</title>
      <link>/posts/minority-report-becomes-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/minority-report-becomes-reality/</guid>
      <description>I was hoping to find a little more time this evening to write up some thoughts about Enterprise Application Development but that&amp;rsquo;s going to have to wait since it&amp;rsquo;s getting late and I have to be up early in the morning.
So for now, I think all of you would enjoy taking a peek at something a good mate of mine in the U.K. (Mark Webster) pointed me at earlier today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It has begun</title>
      <link>/posts/it-has-begun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/it-has-begun/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who know me will know that I generally feel like I have a lot to say :-) I used to write a diary back in the day, but that was quite some time ago and the site, along with its content, is long since dead. For the last couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve been continually reading people&amp;rsquo;s blogs and found they can be quite insightful. As a geek, I tend to read more geek blogs which cover upcoming technologies, opinions on methodologies and other bits of flotsam and jetsam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>