<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marathon on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/tags/marathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in marathon on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/marathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>62 Days To Go</title>
      <link>/posts/62-days-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/62-days-to-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just come back from another run and again I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good. I did the same route as yesterday, but 6 minutes slower. It was encouraging that I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel out of breath or overly tired, the thing that got me was sore legs!
Tomorrow is going to be a rest day because I have to go and do a certification exam during lunch time which is a bit annoying. Hopefully Wednesday lunch time I&amp;rsquo;ll be rested up and ready to take on the lunchtime route again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Training Update</title>
      <link>/posts/marathon-training-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/marathon-training-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since before &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/more-punishment/&#34; title=&#34;More Punishment&#34;&gt;signing up for the marathon&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been making sure that I do my running training regularly. I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing at least 4 runs during the week, pushing for 5 (all during lunch times). The route that I run around the city is approximately 6.2km, which is a good distance to cover while still having time either side of the run for prepration and showering up so that I don&amp;rsquo;t offend my coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Punishment</title>
      <link>/posts/more-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/more-punishment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 3 years on the bench I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take the plunge again. Today I signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goldcoastmarathon.com.au/&#34; title=&#34;Gold Coast Airport Marahon&#34;&gt;Gold Coast Airport Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The event will be held on the 6th July &amp;lsquo;08 &amp;ndash; which from today means I have a total of 80 more days to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been back into running training for a few weeks now, and have been really enjoying it. Lunch time runs are really helping since I don&amp;rsquo;t have a great deal of time in the evenings to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>