<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Programming on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/functional-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Functional Programming on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/functional-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping Down</title>
      <link>/posts/stepping-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/stepping-down/</guid>
      <description>For the past two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been heavily involved with organising two user groups in Brisbane: BFPG and BNoSQL. Those of you out there who organise your own user groups no doubt know how much is involved in keeping these things going. My focus has been on building communities around the subject matter and trying to get attendance up. It was a tough gig.
For the most part I think I succeeded in what I set out to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 5</title>
      <link>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;{% img right /uploads/2010/09/riak-logo.png &amp;lsquo;Riak Logo&amp;rsquo; %}Newcomers to the series should first take a look at the previous four parts of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://buffered.io/series/web-development-with-erlang/&#34; title=&#34;Web Development with Erlang&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-2/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-3/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-4/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 4&#34;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt;) first to make sure that you&amp;rsquo;re up to speed. Feel free to read on if you feel comfortable with the general concepts in use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finished &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-4/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 4&#34;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt; we were able to authenticate users using &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://oauth.net/&#34; title=&#34;OAuth&#34;&gt;OAuth&lt;/a&gt;, which is great as we can delegate the responsibility of password management to an external entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know who people are, we want them to be able to do something meaningful with their accounts. That&amp;rsquo;s what this post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 4</title>
      <link>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;{% img left /uploads/2010/09/riak-logo.png &amp;lsquo;Riak Logo&amp;rsquo; %}For those of you who are new to the series, you may want to check out &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-2/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-3/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; before reading this post. It will help give you some context as well as introduce you to some of the jargon and technology that I&amp;rsquo;m using. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already read then, or don&amp;rsquo;t want to, then please read on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon finishing &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-3/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; of the series we were finally able to read data from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Riak&#34; title=&#34;Riak&#34;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt; and see it appear in our web page. This was the first stage in seeing a full end-to-end web application functioning. Of course there is still a great deal to do!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 3</title>
      <link>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/09/riak-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Riak Logo&#34; style=&#34;float:left;padding-right:5px;padding-bottom:5px;&#34;/&gt;For those of you who are new to the series, you may want to check out &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-2/&#34; title=&#34;Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; before reading this post. It will help give you some context as well as introduce you to some of the jargon and technology that I&amp;rsquo;m using. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already read then, or don&amp;rsquo;t want to, then please read on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post builds on the previous two, but not without a few little modifications. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in following along step by step with your own version of the code running, then get yourself a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OJ/csd/tree/Part2-20110403&#34; title=&#34;Source code for Part 2&#34;&gt;this changeset&lt;/a&gt; before doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A slight refactor of code structure to support the &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; approach to building applications in Erlang using OTP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a small set of modules to talk to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Riak&#34; title=&#34;Riak&#34;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of some &lt;a href=&#34;http://json.org/&#34; title=&#34;JavaScript Object Notation&#34;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt; helper functions for reading and writing data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calling all the way from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Webmachine&#34; title=&#34;Webmachine&#34;&gt;Webmachine&lt;/a&gt; front-end to Riak to extract data and display it in a browser using &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/evanmiller/erlydtl&#34; title=&#34;ErlyDTL&#34;&gt;ErlyDTL&lt;/a&gt; templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few code snippets in this post as well as output from script executions and &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt; sessions. To avoid confusion, all file listings reference the path to the file that is being modified relative to the root of the project folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be warned, this is a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; post :) Get yourself a &lt;em&gt;shmoke und a pancake&lt;/em&gt;, a glass of your favourite beverage and put some relaxing music on (instrumental is best).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you ready? OK, here we go &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/09/riak-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Riak Logo&#34; style=&#34;float:left;padding-right:5px;padding-bottom:5px;&#34;/&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Wembachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of the series we covered the basics of getting the development environment up and running. We also looked at how to get a really simple ErlyDTL template rendering. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet gone through Part 1, I suggest you do that now. If you have, read on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons this series is targeting this technology stack. One of them is &lt;strong&gt;uptime&lt;/strong&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re aiming to build a site that stays up as much as possible. Given that, one of the things that I missed in the previous post was setting up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Load_balancing_(computing)&#34; title=&#34;Load balancing&#34;&gt;load balancer&lt;/a&gt;. Hence this post will attempt to fill that gap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webmachine, ErlyDTL and Riak - Part 1</title>
      <link>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/webmachine-erlydtl-and-riak-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/09/riak-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Riak Logo&#34; style=&#34;float:left;padding-right:5px;padding-bottom:5px;&#34;/&gt;It has been a long time coming, but the first post is finally here! This is the first in a series of post, as &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/the-future-is-erlang/&#34; title=&#34;The Future is Erlang&#34;&gt;promised a while ago&lt;/a&gt;, covering off web development using &lt;a href=&#34;http://erlang.org/&#34; title=&#34;Erlang&#34;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt;. This post is the ubiquitous &amp;ldquo;get up and running&amp;rdquo; post, which aims to get your environment set up so that you can dive in to development. The next post will detail how to handle a basic end-to-end web request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/09/Erlang_logo.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;&#34;/&gt;First up, a few things we need to be aware of before we begin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The information in this post has only been verified on Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxmint.com/&#34; title=&#34;Linux Mint&#34;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; to be exact). It &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; work just fine on Mac OSX. I&amp;rsquo;m almost certain that it &lt;em&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; work on a Windows machine. So if you&amp;rsquo;re a Windows developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait for another post down the track which covers off how to get your environment ready to rock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be downloading, building and installing &lt;a href=&#34;http://erlang.org/&#34; title=&#34;Erlang&#34;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/evanmiller/erlydtl&#34; title=&#34;ErlyDTL&#34;&gt;ErlyDTL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Riak&#34; title=&#34;Riak&#34;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Webmachine&#34; title=&#34;Webmachine&#34;&gt;Webmachine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basho.com/developers.html#Rebar&#34; title=&#34;Rebar&#34;&gt;Rebar&lt;/a&gt; is the tool we&amp;rsquo;ll be using to handle builds, but I won&amp;rsquo;t be covering it in any depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need the latest version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/&#34; title=&#34;Git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; so make sure it&amp;rsquo;s downloaded and installed before you follow this article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be doing &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; interaction with Riak via &lt;a href=&#34;http://curl.haxx.se/&#34; title=&#34;cURL and libcurl&#34;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;, so make sure you have it downloaded and installed as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is intended to be a step-by-step guide targeted at those who are very new to web development in Erlang. This may not be the most ideal set up, nor the best way of doing certain things. I am hoping that those people who are more experienced than I will be able to provide feedback and guidance in areas where I am lacking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over the course of this series I&amp;rsquo;ll be attempting to build an Erlang version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitbucket.org/OJ/codesmackdown&#34; title=&#34;Code Smackdown&#34;&gt;Code Smackdown&lt;/a&gt; site that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on here and there with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://secretgeek.net/&#34; title=&#34;secretGeek&#34;&gt;mate of mine&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll see that the sample application we&amp;rsquo;re working on is called &amp;ldquo;csd&amp;rdquo; for obvious reasons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it. First up, Erlang.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BFPG June Meetup</title>
      <link>/posts/bfpg-june-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bfpg-june-meetup/</guid>
      <description>The time has come for another meeting of the Functional Programming minds! This months BFPG Meetup, starting 6pm Monday 28th, is the first one at our new venue: Microsoft HQ, Waterfront Place, Brisbane. For details on the location, take a look at the BFPG about page.
This month we have three speakers, and I am one of them! In my talk, &amp;ldquo;Erlang - Why should you care?&amp;rdquo;, I will be giving a fairly non-technical introduction to Erlang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Thomas at YOW! Nights Brisbane</title>
      <link>/posts/dave-thomas-at-yow-nights-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dave-thomas-at-yow-nights-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/05/haskell-logo-variation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Haskell Logo&#34; title=&#34;Haskell Logo&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px&#34; /&gt;Two nights ago I was fortunate enough to attend a &lt;a href=&#34;http://yownightbrisbanemay.eventbrite.com/&#34; title=&#34;YOW! Nights Brisbane - May 20th&#34;&gt;YOW! Nights&lt;/a&gt; conference held at the local Microsoft Office here in Brisbane. The speaker for the session was none other than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davethomas.net/&#34; title=&#34;Dave Thomas&#34;&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, the man behind the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;http://objectmentor.com/&#34; title=&#34;Object Mentor&#34;&gt;ObjectMentor&lt;/a&gt;. Not only is this guy incredibly switched on, he is thought-provoking and very entertaining to boot. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a few of these sessions in the past but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen one as packed out as this one. It was great to see such a turn-out, which no doubt was boosted by the presence of both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qmsdnug.org/&#34; title=&#34;QMSDNUG&#34;&gt;Queensland MSDN Users Group&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bfpg.org/&#34; title=&#34;BFPG&#34;&gt;Brisbane Functional Programming Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katacast: Shopping Checkout in Erlang</title>
      <link>/posts/katacast-shopping-checkout-in-erlang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/katacast-shopping-checkout-in-erlang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently discovered the joys of &lt;a href=&#34;http://codekata.pragprog.com/&#34; title=&#34;CodeKata&#34;&gt;CodeKatas&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re a geek looking for a way to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Seven_Habits_of_Highly_Effective_People&#34; title=&#34;The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People&#34;&gt;sharpen the saw&lt;/a&gt; then I highly recommend taking a look at these and trying a few out. They&amp;rsquo;re great fun and they&amp;rsquo;re a good way of getting your feet wet with new languages (especially if you&amp;rsquo;re tired of &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future is Erlang</title>
      <link>/posts/the-future-is-erlang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-future-is-erlang/</guid>
      <description>For quite a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my spare cycles to chew over a problem. This problem is not one that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been solved before, but one that I feel can be solved in a much better way. From the bit of research that I&amp;rsquo;ve done, I can see at least three areas which can be improved on dramatically. So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided, after a long period of deliberation, to go ahead and build my solution and release it to the world as a service!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haskell 101 at the Brisbane Functional Programming Meetup</title>
      <link>/posts/haskell-101-at-the-brisbane-functional-programming-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/haskell-101-at-the-brisbane-functional-programming-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d let the world know that tomorrow night, at 6pm AEST, the Brisbane Functional Programming Group is having another get-together. The topics for the meeting are:  Introduction to Functional Programming - by Brad Clow Haskell 101 - by me!  There are still spots available if you&amp;rsquo;re keen to come along. It should be fun!
I&amp;rsquo;m always up for some public scrutiny, so come along and bring your rotten tomatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Point-Free style: What is it good for?&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/point-free-style-what-is-it-good-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/point-free-style-what-is-it-good-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in what inspired this post, then skip this section and &lt;a href=&#34;#MoreInteresting&#34; title=&#34;The purpose of the post&#34;&gt;jump&lt;/a&gt; to the more interesting bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-little-bit-of-history&#34;&gt;A Little Bit of History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been delving into &lt;a href=&#34;http://haskell.org/&#34; title=&#34;Haskell&#34;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt; quite a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s part of my apparently never-ending quest to learn as much as I can about as many languages as I can (well, those that appeal to me at least :)). While I love playing around with a language, toying with ideas, writing small programs, reading books, blog posts, etc it&amp;rsquo;s not really the same as having an on-call expert to help and guide you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Crunching in Haskell</title>
      <link>/posts/data-crunching-in-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-crunching-in-haskell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I was having a chat to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiftperception.com/blog&#34; title=&#34;Shifty&#34;&gt;friend of mine&lt;/a&gt; about a little data parsing problem. He had the need to parse a multi-dimensional array to pull out some values. That array was guaranteed to be square, but not necessarily in contiguous memory. He needed to parse each &amp;ldquo;column&amp;rdquo; of the array, calculate a total, and then determine the biggest and smallest of those totals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sample of the data might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;data = ({150,200,45,57,95,2,45,32,15,10,5,2,2,4},
        {12,20,45,37,10,5,2,2,10,95,2,45,32,7},
        {32,15,10,5,2,23,24,15,20,45,57,95,0,45})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first step would be to add 150, 12 and 32 and store the value. Then 200, 20 and 15, and store the value. Do this for all of the columns, then get a maximum and a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #10</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #10 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Quick Coding Challenge</title>
      <link>/posts/another-quick-coding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/another-quick-coding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was about to head to bed when I stumbled across another interesting coding challenge. Since I had another half hour or so to kill I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a shot!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #9</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #9 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #8</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #8 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating use of Parenthesis</title>
      <link>/posts/validating-use-of-parenthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/validating-use-of-parenthesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dev102.com/posts/a-programming-job-interview-challenge-13-brackets/&#34; title=&#34;Programming Challenge&#34;&gt;programming challenge appeared on dev102&lt;/a&gt; the other day, and I thought that this time I&amp;rsquo;d post my solution here in the blog rather than letting it get lost in the depths of the comment thread!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #7</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #7 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Little Problem</title>
      <link>/posts/an-interesting-little-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-interesting-little-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was inspired by a recent interview question that was posted over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsharp.it/posts/google-interview-question-product-of-other-elements-in-an-array-in-on/&#34; title=&#34;Fsharp.it&#34;&gt;fsharp.it&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those neat little questions which looks really simple on the surface but is quite tricky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #6</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #6 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #5</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #5 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #4 - Reprise</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#4-reprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#4-reprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After publishing the performance stats of my &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/project-euler-4/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler #4&#34;&gt;previous solution to Project Euler #4&lt;/a&gt;, I got thinking about how I might improve things. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be overly anal with regards to things such as memory allocations, because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get stuck in the perpetual loop of attempted optimisations. Instead I wanted to think of a method that wasn&amp;rsquo;t as brute force as the previous one. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested to see what I did, read on (&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a spoiler for the problem, just like the last post was).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #4</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #4 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #3</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #3 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #2</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #2 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Geek Interests</title>
      <link>/posts/current-geek-interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/current-geek-interests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the weeks roll by I&amp;rsquo;m finding that I have less and less time to chase up anything geek-related. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not alone ;) Responsibilities and life take over and that time which you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; invest is now invested in other things, such as &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/my-boy/&#34; title=&#34;My Boy&#34;&gt;children&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m dedicating this post to all those things that I currently find interesting and would love to invest time in. Some of these things are old, some new. All of them I&amp;rsquo;ve either not touched on at all, or have touched on only briefly (not enough to be satisfied). I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share them with you in case you find them interesting yourself, or perhaps have some insights which you&amp;rsquo;d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler #1</title>
      <link>/posts/project-euler-#1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-euler-#1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This post contains a spoiler for Problem #1 listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net/&#34; title=&#34;Project Euler&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. Do not read the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attempt to solve the problem yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rekindling my Functional Programming Passion with Haskell</title>
      <link>/posts/rekindling-my-functional-programming-passion-with-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rekindling-my-functional-programming-passion-with-haskell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the day when I was studying at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uts.edu.au/&#34; title=&#34;UTS&#34;&gt;University&lt;/a&gt; I tutored a subject which taught students how to write functional code in &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Miranda&lt;/a&gt;. I loved it! The whole &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming&#34; title=&#34;Functional Programming&#34;&gt;functional programming&lt;/a&gt; thing really did it for me. I was fascinated by it. Despite my interest, I never chased it up after finishing at University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled on a random blog post that went into depth on some functional programming topics, and that resparked my interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>