<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Rights on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/digital-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Rights on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/digital-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactivate? AGAIN!?</title>
      <link>/posts/reactivate-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reactivate-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post to say how much Microsoft and their draconian OS licensing mechanism are pissing me off right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my computer stopped booting. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to looking at it until a few days ago because I had visitors over from the UK. Not just that, it is Christmas, and the last thing you want to be doing on your Christmas break is to be fixing computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biosham &amp;#8482;</title>
      <link>/posts/biosham-#8482/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/biosham-#8482/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can fully understand the desire a developer has to protect their creation from being copied illegally. I can understand why some steps would be taken to mitigate the risk of losing money due to piracy. What I can&amp;rsquo;t understand is why some companies go &lt;em&gt;so far&lt;/em&gt; with their anti-piracy measures that it starts to have an impact on the honourable, paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/microsoft-vista-licence-restrictions/&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Vista License Restrictions&#34;&gt;bitched&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/office-registration-and-activation/&#34; title=&#34;Office Registratoin and Activation&#34;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; about how activation is a pain in the neck. But that example is nothing like what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/&#34; title=&#34;2K Games&#34;&gt;2K Games&lt;/a&gt; have recently inflicted on the buyers of their latest creation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/bioshock/&#34; title=&#34;Bioshock&#34;&gt;Bioshock&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than throw a few links to a bzillion blog and forum posts that have covered it already, let me just give you the short version:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bioshock comes with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securom.com/&#34; title=&#34;SecuROM&#34;&gt;SecuROM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It requires online activation before it can be played.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It can only be activated &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;On the surface this might not sound so bad, but when you think about it a little deeper it becomes obvious why this is such a pain in the arse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll View What I Like!</title>
      <link>/posts/ill-view-what-i-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ill-view-what-i-like/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a few questions for you:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;How would you feel if TV channels changed automatically because you weren&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to the ads?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would you like it if your newspaper closed by itself because you were reading the articles but skipping over the classifieds?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How happy would you be if you were kicked out of a cinema for not watching the latest and greatest in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.valmorgan.com.au/&#34; title=&#34;Val Morgan&#34;&gt;Val Morgan Cinema Advertising&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would you be happy if you weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to walk into a shop unless you HAD to buy something?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you&amp;rsquo;d be pretty pissed off about it. The scary thing is that this kind of thing is already happening on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg is Being Used Against Itself</title>
      <link>/posts/digg-is-being-used-against-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/digg-is-being-used-against-itself/</guid>
      <description>Over the last day or so, stacks of people have been hammering digg as a revolt against their recent actions. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, HD-DVD encryption was cracked recently and the master key which allows all movies to be ripped has been released across the web. Digg, in their infinite wisdom, decided to kill off the original blog post (and apparently banned one or two users? - unconfirmed), resulting in an avalanche of posts preaching &amp;ldquo;free speach&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;fuck you Digg&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it Becoming Illegal to do Anything?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-it-becoming-illegal-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-it-becoming-illegal-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel that over time the world is getting harder to live in. To be a bit more precise, it&amp;rsquo;s becoming very difficult to do anything at all for fear of putting yourself in the firing line, or on the receiving end of a law suit. Two things that have caught my attention over the last couple of weeks which have really annoyed me. One of them is down to the frustration I feel when people are trying to get something for nothing, and the other is down to annoyance at regulations that are put in place which are just totally ridiculous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVD Cracker Nails Apple&#39;s iPod Code</title>
      <link>/posts/dvd-cracker-nails-apples-ipod-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dvd-cracker-nails-apples-ipod-code/</guid>
      <description>You gotta hand it to this guy, he says that he &amp;ldquo;doesn&amp;rsquo;t like closed systems&amp;rdquo;, which is pretty darned obvious :) The man, Jon Lech Johansen, who years ago cracked the DVD encryption known as CSS, and released (with two other unknowns) the software that could be used to decrypt DVDs (called DeCSS), has taken his code-breaking career to a new level - he&amp;rsquo;s nailed Apple iPod&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem (or so he claims) by breaking their FairPlay DRM software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pox on your DRM</title>
      <link>/posts/a-pox-on-your-drm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-pox-on-your-drm/</guid>
      <description>I can no longer resist the temptation to talk about DRM (at least in part) after the issues that I faced over the weekend. I know I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one that has experienced the pain that I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pissed off about it.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to be getting married pretty soon, and as a result my fiance and I are both trying to finalise arrangements for the wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>