<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to an Australian Games Industry Icon</title>
      <link>/posts/farewell-to-an-australian-games-industry-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/farewell-to-an-australian-games-industry-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a bit of sad news from &amp;ldquo;He who must not be named&amp;rdquo; this morning. It appears that Aussie game developer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.auran.com/&#34; title=&#34;Auran&#34;&gt;Auran&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href=&#34;http://kotaku.com/gaming/rumor/auran-on-life-support-330643.php&#34; title=&#34;Auran on Life-Support&#34;&gt;struggling to stay afloat&lt;/a&gt;, and will most likely close. This isn&amp;rsquo;t good news for the Aussie contingent of the games industry, and is an indication of how cut-throat the industry can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, while it&amp;rsquo;s sad to hear that they&amp;rsquo;re in strife, it isn&amp;rsquo;t really a &lt;em&gt;surprise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biosham &amp;#8482;</title>
      <link>/posts/biosham-#8482/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/biosham-#8482/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can fully understand the desire a developer has to protect their creation from being copied illegally. I can understand why some steps would be taken to mitigate the risk of losing money due to piracy. What I can&amp;rsquo;t understand is why some companies go &lt;em&gt;so far&lt;/em&gt; with their anti-piracy measures that it starts to have an impact on the honourable, paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/microsoft-vista-licence-restrictions/&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Vista License Restrictions&#34;&gt;bitched&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/office-registration-and-activation/&#34; title=&#34;Office Registratoin and Activation&#34;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; about how activation is a pain in the neck. But that example is nothing like what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/&#34; title=&#34;2K Games&#34;&gt;2K Games&lt;/a&gt; have recently inflicted on the buyers of their latest creation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/bioshock/&#34; title=&#34;Bioshock&#34;&gt;Bioshock&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than throw a few links to a bzillion blog and forum posts that have covered it already, let me just give you the short version:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bioshock comes with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securom.com/&#34; title=&#34;SecuROM&#34;&gt;SecuROM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It requires online activation before it can be played.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It can only be activated &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;On the surface this might not sound so bad, but when you think about it a little deeper it becomes obvious why this is such a pain in the arse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gaming Round-Up</title>
      <link>/posts/a-gaming-round-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-gaming-round-up/</guid>
      <description>I have quite a bit to cover in the gaming world today, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to create a separate post for each thing so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d group them all together.
So to start off with, there&amp;rsquo;s been some buzz around town that some &amp;ldquo;demo&amp;rdquo; PS3s have made a bit of an appearance. The guys at IGN have been given a bit of a hands-on session with the PS3! It&amp;rsquo;s hard to call bullshit when there&amp;rsquo;s photos of dudes playing the console, so I&amp;rsquo;ll hold myself back for now ;) The article is quite interesting, and in my (humble) opinion doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give the PS3 a resounding thumbs up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All joking aside, I have to have a Wii</title>
      <link>/posts/all-joking-aside-i-have-to-have-a-wii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/all-joking-aside-i-have-to-have-a-wii/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a gamer for a very long time. My interest in games is what launched my programming career, and as a young kid I used to spend hours trying to figure out how those games worked on my Commodore Vic 20. Peeking and Poking was as far as I got in those days, but the interest has been around since. For many years I worked hard to try and get a job in the games industry, and with the industry here in Australia being quite hard to get into I decided to head to the U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>