<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Being in the Industry on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/being-in-the-industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Being in the Industry on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/being-in-the-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping Down</title>
      <link>/posts/stepping-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/stepping-down/</guid>
      <description>For the past two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been heavily involved with organising two user groups in Brisbane: BFPG and BNoSQL. Those of you out there who organise your own user groups no doubt know how much is involved in keeping these things going. My focus has been on building communities around the subject matter and trying to get attendance up. It was a tough gig.
For the most part I think I succeeded in what I set out to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Expert at 23</title>
      <link>/posts/an-expert-at-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-expert-at-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was about to head to bed when I stumbled across a poorly-titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news.com.au/business/the-best-places-to-look-for-work-in-2012/story-e6frfm1i-1226255099978&#34; title=&#34;The best places to look for work in 2012&#34;&gt;article on news.com.au&lt;/a&gt;. At first I thought it was going to cover off the best locations around Australia, or perhaps the world, for finding work in a variety of industries. It turned out to be a failed attempt at highlighting the key growth industry areas for jobs in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It began like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JOBS demanded across several booming sectors will be the best place to find work this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the appalling structure and lack of coherence of the opening paragraph I pushed on through the rest of the article, hoping to find some interesting or useful information. Most of content would be fairly obvious to almost every Australian. The bits that could be considered interesting were old news, and nothing in the article made me feel that reading it was a good use of time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I use Twitter</title>
      <link>/posts/why-i-use-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-i-use-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first signed up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; back in mid-2008 I didn&amp;rsquo;t really take it seriously. My view was that it was a toy and one that I intended to have a bit of fun with. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think that it would turn into what it did. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t think it would be such an amazing source of information, nor did I expect it to give me contact with so many smart and interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Thomas at YOW! Nights Brisbane</title>
      <link>/posts/dave-thomas-at-yow-nights-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dave-thomas-at-yow-nights-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/05/haskell-logo-variation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Haskell Logo&#34; title=&#34;Haskell Logo&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px&#34; /&gt;Two nights ago I was fortunate enough to attend a &lt;a href=&#34;http://yownightbrisbanemay.eventbrite.com/&#34; title=&#34;YOW! Nights Brisbane - May 20th&#34;&gt;YOW! Nights&lt;/a&gt; conference held at the local Microsoft Office here in Brisbane. The speaker for the session was none other than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davethomas.net/&#34; title=&#34;Dave Thomas&#34;&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, the man behind the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;http://objectmentor.com/&#34; title=&#34;Object Mentor&#34;&gt;ObjectMentor&lt;/a&gt;. Not only is this guy incredibly switched on, he is thought-provoking and very entertaining to boot. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a few of these sessions in the past but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen one as packed out as this one. It was great to see such a turn-out, which no doubt was boosted by the presence of both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qmsdnug.org/&#34; title=&#34;QMSDNUG&#34;&gt;Queensland MSDN Users Group&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bfpg.org/&#34; title=&#34;BFPG&#34;&gt;Brisbane Functional Programming Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Issue of Perception</title>
      <link>/posts/the-issue-of-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-issue-of-perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-perception&#34;&gt;What is Perception?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As cheesy as it sounds, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start off with a definition ripped straight off &lt;a href=&#34;http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/perception&#34; title=&#34;Perception | Define Perception at Dictionary.com&#34;&gt;Dictionary.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;perception&#34;&gt;perception&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;noun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the act or faculty of apprehending by means of the senses or of the mind; cognition; understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;immediate or intuitive recognition or appreciation, as of moral, psychological, or aesthetic qualities; insight; intuition; discernment: &lt;em&gt;an artist of rare perception&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the result or product of perceiving, as distinguished from the act of perceiving; percept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychology&lt;/em&gt;. a single unified awareness derived from sensory processes while a stimulus is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law. the taking into possession of rents, crops, profits, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2010/03/escher.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34; title=&#34;A classic Escher&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/03/escher.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A classic Escher&#34; title=&#34;A classic Escher&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 5px; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Take a moment to digest the meaning of the word. Can you see how subjective it is? One&amp;rsquo;s perception varies greatly depending on the observer. The motivation of the observation is also going to skew how one is perceived. The relationship one has with the observer is also going to impact how that observer perceives you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that what was &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; and any point in time is not necessarily the same as what &lt;strong&gt;actually occurred&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m so impressed I want to pay you less</title>
      <link>/posts/im-so-impressed-i-want-to-pay-you-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/im-so-impressed-i-want-to-pay-you-less/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2010/03/statue-of-liberty_whip_ny-times.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Slave driver&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox[slave]&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/03/statue-of-liberty_whip_ny-times.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Slave driver&#34; title=&#34;Slave driver&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-bottom: 5px; margin-right: 5px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The title of this post is a statement that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a few times in the past while at work. The people who said it might not have used those exact words, but the intent is the same. Usually I hear it in the following form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re very happy with the work you&amp;rsquo;ve done for us as a contractor. We want to keep you on, but would like you to take a job as a permanent employee and continue to work on the project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they&amp;rsquo;ve made this point, they then feel the need to harp on about the good points of becoming a permanent employee. Things such as job security, sick/annual leave and better hours tend to get mentioned. All of them are complete bullshit of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;strong&gt;no such thing as job security&lt;/strong&gt;. Sick and/or annual leave isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to make up for the difference in pay. Hours tend to always be worse when you&amp;rsquo;re working for the man, because you&amp;rsquo;re expected to do whatever needs to be done regardless of the hours. This is worse if you&amp;rsquo;re working on mission-critical stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wrong Decision by the Wrong Person</title>
      <link>/posts/the-wrong-decision-by-the-wrong-person/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-wrong-decision-by-the-wrong-person/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2010/01/pizza.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The wrong tool.&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2010/01/pizza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The wrong tool.&#34; title=&#34;The wrong tool.&#34; style=&#34;float:right; margin-left:5px; margin-bottom:5px;&#34;  width=&#34;150&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There is one thing about my industry that I still find truly amazing (and not in a good way). This is despite the fact that it has happened to me so many times that you think I&amp;rsquo;d be used to it! I&amp;rsquo;m talking about non-technical people making technical decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, it&amp;rsquo;s a very common practice for those people who don&amp;rsquo;t have expertise in a certain field to make decisions for people working in that field. The best example I can think of off the top of my head is the answer to the question: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which technology should we use?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me take a step back in time for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;It&#39;s OK to Fail</title>
      <link>/posts/its-ok-to-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/its-ok-to-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2009/12/EpicFail02.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox[fail]&#34; title=&#34;Epic Fail&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2009/12/EpicFail02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Epic Fail&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; style=&#34;float:left;padding-bottom:5px;padding-right:5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes. You read that right. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to fail. Yes, I am talking to you. You&amp;hellip; that guy who is part of every team. The one who seems to feel the need to be right about everything. The one who thinks that everything new has already been done 15 years prior. The one who believes that every project they have participated in has been a profound success, and that a project-level failure (which includes missing deadlines or blowing the budget) is something they have never experienced. Failure is not only OK, it&amp;rsquo;s something that you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; experience somewhere along the way so you know when you&amp;rsquo;ve succeeded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of a Technical Community</title>
      <link>/posts/the-value-of-a-technical-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-value-of-a-technical-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2009/07/community.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;lightbox&#34; title=&#34;Cricket Team Holding Hands --- Image by  Royalty-Free/Corbis&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2009/07/community.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cricket Team Holding Hands --- Image by  Royalty-Free/Corbis&#34; title=&#34;Cricket Team Holding Hands --- Image by  Royalty-Free/Corbis&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 5px; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This post was inspired by an experience I had recently in an IRC channel. To protect the innocent, I&amp;rsquo;ll refrain from naming and shaming the channel and individual as those details aren&amp;rsquo;t important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communities are arguably the life blood of technology. Without a good community the likelihood of the technology catching on is drastically reduced. Those communities which lack individuals that are happy to put time and effort in to help get others up to speed tend to stagnate. Any community which involves members that are abrasive, rude and downright offensive is destined to suffer long term.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Need Your Frickin&#39; Framework!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-dont-need-your-frickin-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/i-dont-need-your-frickin-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/uploads/2009/04/scaffold_fail.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Scaffold Fail&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/uploads/2009/04/scaffold_fail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Scaffold Fail&#34; title=&#34;Scaffold Fail&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 5px; margin-bottom: 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How many companies have you worked with/for that have their own framework? How many have been in the process of developing their own framework? How many have been in the process of &lt;strong&gt;re&lt;/strong&gt;developing their own framework? How many have taken another framework and &lt;del&gt;hacked&lt;/del&gt; improved it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I attempt to answer the questions listed above, I start to shiver. I feel the need to burn my clothes and take a very long shower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites are Hard to Build - A Case in Point</title>
      <link>/posts/websites-are-hard-to-build-a-case-in-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/websites-are-hard-to-build-a-case-in-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short time ago I &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/websites-are-hard-to-build/&#34; title=&#34;Websites are Hard to Build&#34;&gt;posted some thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on issues faced when building websites that most people aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of when they decide to have one built. I posted from the perspective of someone who has, on many occasions, been asked to build a site for someone who really doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a clue about what is involved. More importantly, they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are people out there who don&amp;rsquo;t know about the issues faced, but are still in need of a site to fulfil their needs. Should they learn about these issues themselves? Should they put their faith in a developer/designer and let them do their job and just send them a bill at the end? A mixture of the two?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to an Australian Games Industry Icon</title>
      <link>/posts/farewell-to-an-australian-games-industry-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/farewell-to-an-australian-games-industry-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a bit of sad news from &amp;ldquo;He who must not be named&amp;rdquo; this morning. It appears that Aussie game developer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.auran.com/&#34; title=&#34;Auran&#34;&gt;Auran&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href=&#34;http://kotaku.com/gaming/rumor/auran-on-life-support-330643.php&#34; title=&#34;Auran on Life-Support&#34;&gt;struggling to stay afloat&lt;/a&gt;, and will most likely close. This isn&amp;rsquo;t good news for the Aussie contingent of the games industry, and is an indication of how cut-throat the industry can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, while it&amp;rsquo;s sad to hear that they&amp;rsquo;re in strife, it isn&amp;rsquo;t really a &lt;em&gt;surprise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biosham &amp;#8482;</title>
      <link>/posts/biosham-#8482/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/biosham-#8482/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can fully understand the desire a developer has to protect their creation from being copied illegally. I can understand why some steps would be taken to mitigate the risk of losing money due to piracy. What I can&amp;rsquo;t understand is why some companies go &lt;em&gt;so far&lt;/em&gt; with their anti-piracy measures that it starts to have an impact on the honourable, paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/microsoft-vista-licence-restrictions/&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Vista License Restrictions&#34;&gt;bitched&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/office-registration-and-activation/&#34; title=&#34;Office Registratoin and Activation&#34;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; about how activation is a pain in the neck. But that example is nothing like what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/&#34; title=&#34;2K Games&#34;&gt;2K Games&lt;/a&gt; have recently inflicted on the buyers of their latest creation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2kgames.com/bioshock/&#34; title=&#34;Bioshock&#34;&gt;Bioshock&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than throw a few links to a bzillion blog and forum posts that have covered it already, let me just give you the short version:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bioshock comes with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securom.com/&#34; title=&#34;SecuROM&#34;&gt;SecuROM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It requires online activation before it can be played.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It can only be activated &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;On the surface this might not sound so bad, but when you think about it a little deeper it becomes obvious why this is such a pain in the arse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misled from the Start</title>
      <link>/posts/misled-from-the-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/misled-from-the-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find myself frequently concerned with the lack of ability of a lot of people in our industry. Today I found an example of at least one of the possible reasons why software development professionals turn out to be crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They start by reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://mezzoscorner.blogspot.com/2007/07/basics-your-first-program.html&#34; title=&#34;The Basics - Your first program&#34;&gt;tutorials like this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we expect people to become good at what they do if the tutorials they&amp;rsquo;re learning from are like that? If you learn the bad stuff from the outset then you&amp;rsquo;re destined to be writing bad code for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Geek Part 3: The Game Geek</title>
      <link>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-3-the-game-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-3-the-game-geek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the next in the Becoming a Geek series. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the areas which I think a budding Game Geek needs to be adept in for him/her to be a true Game Geek. I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a clear distinction from the start that the Game Geek is a different beast to a Game &lt;em&gt;Development&lt;/em&gt; Geek, and hence I won&amp;rsquo;t be covering the development side in this post. I will, however, be covering the game development details in a later post in this series on the Development Geek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Geek Part 2: The Web Geek</title>
      <link>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-2-the-web-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-2-the-web-geek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to part 2 of my Becoming a Geek series. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already read part 1, I suggest you read it first. Before you can be a web geek, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to be a &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-1-the-general-geek/&#34; title=&#34;Becoming a Geek Part 1: The General Geek&#34;&gt;General Geek&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re already on the way to becoming a General Geek, here are a stack of hints to help you become a Web Geek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Geek Part 1: The General Geek</title>
      <link>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-1-the-general-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/becoming-a-geek-part-1-the-general-geek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, there are many types of geek. In this series, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give some basic tips on how to become one!  This is the first part in the series, and so I&amp;rsquo;m covering the &amp;lsquo;General Geek&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I even went to university to get qualifications to become an official &amp;ldquo;paid&amp;rdquo; geek, I put a great deal of time and effort into tuning my skills in other areas that would help me excel at my job. Below is a list of things that I did which I believe really helped me achieve my goal, and I would recommend doing the same if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to become a paid geek yourself!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you Enjoy what you do for a Living?</title>
      <link>/posts/do-you-enjoy-what-you-do-for-a-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/do-you-enjoy-what-you-do-for-a-living/</guid>
      <description>I remember when I was in high school as a teenager and all I wanted to &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo; was a Software Engineer. I was one of those lucky people who always seemed to know what it is they wanted to do, and for me it was always going to be creating software. I got stuck into a plethora of coding projects in my own time while finishing school which, along with doing &amp;ldquo;Computer Studies&amp;rdquo; for the last 3 years, gave me a pretty solid grounding to build on when I got to University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Can&#39;t Programmers Program?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-cant-programmers-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-cant-programmers-program/</guid>
      <description>While reading The Daily Grind from Larkware I found myself reading through a couple of articles (here and here) on programmers not being able to program. This obviously caught my interest as I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with my fair share of these &amp;ldquo;programmers&amp;rdquo; in the past. It got me thinking about how to determine whether or not someone is good in an interview, how their background affects the way they perform when they start working as a developer, and whether or not having N years of experience actually means N years of experience or simply N lots of 1 years experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Parable of the Two Programmers</title>
      <link>/posts/the-parable-of-the-two-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-parable-of-the-two-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Another short snippet this morning. I wanted to inform you of a fairly old-skool story; one that lots of developers will already know about. It&amp;rsquo;s a great tale, and still holds a lot of truth for today&amp;rsquo;s world of I.T. despite it being very old.
Have a read of the tale - The Parable of the Two Programmers.
Which one are you? :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Software List is Not a Job Description</title>
      <link>/posts/a-software-list-is-not-a-job-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-software-list-is-not-a-job-description/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve had the joy of dealing with many recruitment agents as I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a new contract. I won&amp;rsquo;t get into the choice of job at this stage, as that&amp;rsquo;s a whole new blog post right there. What I wanted to show was my frustration at quality of most of the job advertisements I see on the Internet.
To sum up:They generally have a lot of spelling and grammatical errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life, the Universe and Everything.</title>
      <link>/posts/life-the-universe-and-everything./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/life-the-universe-and-everything./</guid>
      <description>42??
It&amp;rsquo;s been quite some time since I&amp;rsquo;ve had a proper rant, and now that the wedding is over and I have a bit more spare time I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take the chance to dump some more thoughts about something we all want to know about &amp;hellip; stuff!!
Today&amp;rsquo;s stuff regards issues around work-life balance and what makes me happy doing what I do for a living. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a broad topic, but one that I consider to be pretty damned important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers vs Programmers</title>
      <link>/posts/developers-vs-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/developers-vs-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Which one are you? I&amp;rsquo;ve had my own thoughts on the differences between what makes a person a developer and what makes a person a programmer for some time, but I think this article at Hacknot bears a striking resemblance - which means I don&amp;rsquo;t have to write it out myself :)
A great read, and it&amp;rsquo;s something that not only hilights the differences between a lot of people you&amp;rsquo;ll find out there working in the industry, but it&amp;rsquo;ll give an idea of what I believe should be expected of you while you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do your job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sauce</title>
      <link>/posts/open-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/open-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in Open Source Software (OSS) for quite some time now but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really attempted to find out much about it, nor how I can contribute. Of course, being a professional developer, the immediate thought is &amp;ldquo;I make a living off writing software, so how does that work with Open Source?&amp;rdquo;.
After reading all the news about Vista and it&amp;rsquo;s attempts to completely revoke my rights as a user, my interest in the OSS movement in general has increased, and I do feel it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to not only get a better understanding of what it is and how it works, but how I can contribute to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Code Security</title>
      <link>/posts/learning-code-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learning-code-security/</guid>
      <description>As a regular read of Scott Gu&amp;rsquo;s blog (see blogroll) I often find nuggets of information that are handy for the work that I do, but I also often end up with a few questions :)
The latest one that fired up a bit of thought was his post on guarding against SQL injection attacks. The information posted very handy, and is something that I would assume most web developers already know, but it made me wonder how many devs out there are actually aware of these kinds of issues while they&amp;rsquo;re building their applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day Job</title>
      <link>/posts/the-day-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-day-job/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been intending to write about this (and a few other things) for a while now, but due to wedding planning and work I&amp;rsquo;ve found it hard to find the time. So I&amp;rsquo;ll take the opportunity while my disk is being defragged to crank out some thoughts.
Individual developers vary in many different ways, but I&amp;rsquo;ve often wondered what motivates other people and what they consider their job to be. To be more specific, what is it that a developer feels they should be doing in their day job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does a qualification make a difference?</title>
      <link>/posts/does-a-qualification-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/does-a-qualification-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>I have pondered this question since long before I graduated from University. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with a mix of degree-qualified and self-taught people, and I&amp;rsquo;m still yet to nail the answer.
Being degree-qualified or self-taught both have their pros and cons, but at the end of the day I think that the person who has a good mix of both sides is the one that&amp;rsquo;s going to stand out. If you&amp;rsquo;re keen to make a go of your career then you should want to give yourself the best chance of getting work in the field by studying it formally at University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Productivity Utopia</title>
      <link>/posts/finding-productivity-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/finding-productivity-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Productivity. It&amp;rsquo;s something that all of us, as developers, should be finding ways to increase. I say should because I know of a stack of people out there who don&amp;rsquo;t. In fact, there&amp;rsquo;s a surprising amount of people out there who are not only not looking to find ways to increase productivity, they seem to go out of their way to reduce it - and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t just affect their own output, it affects that of the people they work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you any good?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-you-any-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/are-you-any-good/</guid>
      <description>I was trundling through my usual collection of daily links yesterday morning (before diving into my work), and I stumbled on a link to a recent blog post by a chap called Peter Wright. There are a couple of reasons why this blog post caught my eye.
First of all, during my time in the U.K. over the last couple of years, I worked for a company in London that Peter also worked at.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>