<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on OJ&#39;s Perspective</title>
    <link>/categories/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on OJ&#39;s Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright OJ Reeves 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another New Keyboard</title>
      <link>/posts/another-new-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/another-new-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/a-hardware-update/&#34; title=&#34;A Hardware Update&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about some new hardware that I bought. In that update I mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;d bought a new keyboard because my old one was a bit shaky and had the old UK layout which was no longer valid since I have now returned to Australia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hardware Update</title>
      <link>/posts/a-hardware-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-hardware-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in a previous post, I have been getting tired of the keyboard that I have at home. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it since December 2004, and it&amp;rsquo;s well past its use-by date. I bought it while living in the UK and hence it has the UK keyboard layout. This was fine while I &lt;em&gt;lived&lt;/em&gt; in the UK, but has been a nuisance since being back in Australia. Every other keyboard that I use has the US layout. So every time I come home I end up making mistakes while typing because keys aren&amp;rsquo;t where my head thinks they are! Aside from the layout issue, some keys were starting to get a bit dodgey and were failing to recognise keypresses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactivate? AGAIN!?</title>
      <link>/posts/reactivate-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reactivate-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post to say how much Microsoft and their draconian OS licensing mechanism are pissing me off right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my computer stopped booting. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to looking at it until a few days ago because I had visitors over from the UK. Not just that, it is Christmas, and the last thing you want to be doing on your Christmas break is to be fixing computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quiet Purchase</title>
      <link>/posts/a-quiet-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-quiet-purchase/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I bought something that I know I should have bought a long time ago. In fact, I should have bought it at the same time that I bought my video card. In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, the stock fan that comes with this video card is by far the noisiest ever. It&amp;rsquo;s the loudest in their line of video cards, and I think it might even be the loudest across all cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it Becoming Illegal to do Anything?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-it-becoming-illegal-to-do-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/is-it-becoming-illegal-to-do-anything/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel that over time the world is getting harder to live in. To be a bit more precise, it&amp;rsquo;s becoming very difficult to do anything at all for fear of putting yourself in the firing line, or on the receiving end of a law suit. Two things that have caught my attention over the last couple of weeks which have really annoyed me. One of them is down to the frustration I feel when people are trying to get something for nothing, and the other is down to annoyance at regulations that are put in place which are just totally ridiculous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Screen Development</title>
      <link>/posts/dual-screen-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dual-screen-development/</guid>
      <description>As it tends to be with many things in life, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t see the need for multiple monitors until I had the experience myself. Up until my time at the game dev studio in the U.K. (which will remain anonymous :)), I had no idea what it was like to work on a machine that had more than one monitor. Within a week, there was no going back!
Those of you who use at least two monitors for day to day work will know what I&amp;rsquo;m going to say in this post - those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t (and in particular, never have done) should listen and listen good!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All joking aside, I have to have a Wii</title>
      <link>/posts/all-joking-aside-i-have-to-have-a-wii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/all-joking-aside-i-have-to-have-a-wii/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a gamer for a very long time. My interest in games is what launched my programming career, and as a young kid I used to spend hours trying to figure out how those games worked on my Commodore Vic 20. Peeking and Poking was as far as I got in those days, but the interest has been around since. For many years I worked hard to try and get a job in the games industry, and with the industry here in Australia being quite hard to get into I decided to head to the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiedererlangen von einem toten Computer</title>
      <link>/posts/wiedererlangen-von-einem-toten-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wiedererlangen-von-einem-toten-computer/</guid>
      <description>Computer failures. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been bitten by them, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we&amp;rsquo;ll all be bitten by them again. Good quality HDD storage is becoming more common, but despite the advances in technology, our drives still only have a reliable lifetime of a few years. Power supplies are becoming more solid, but they still blow up. Motherboards, while having more features than you poke a stick at, are still susceptable to being killed by something as simple as static electricity at the slightest touch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>